AMADOU LAMINE GAYE

Email: <u>laminegaye@me.com</u> Mobile: +44-7983-236364

SUMMARY

An AWS Certified Solutions Architect with a strong passion for the Cloud, Serverless and machine learning technologies seeking opportunity to build and help build business value through technology.

A versatile, analytical and self-motivated professional with a diverse experience in various industries including 6 years trading financial derivatives at top-tiers banks and 7 years self-funded entrepreneurship in agricultural cultivation and logistics. A highly adaptable multilingual team player, with advanced fluency in Japanese and French, experience of data analysis in Python/R and model training with deep learning frameworks such as PyTorch and fastai, who can bring unique skills to any team.

EXPERIENCE

Lamaranji SARL – Dakar / London Founder and General Manager

October 2012 – March 2019

- Built an entirely self-funded business of fruits, vegetables and rice production in North-Senegal, with 50ha of river irrigated plantations. Auxiliary businesses include plant hire services, plantation development, soil improvement, irrigation systems.
- Pioneered solar-powered irrigation in the region, as well as novel fodder crops, and symbiotic association of produce (fodder, fruits, vegetable) and animal farming.

Daiwa Securities Capital Markets – Tokyo, Japan June 2009 – August 2012 Director, Equity Hybrids Trading, Fixed Income Currency and Commodities Division

- Traded the largest Equity Index Hybrids book in Japan, covering long-dated equity coupons, equity-interest rate and equity-FX hybrids. Also managed the short-dated equity auto-callable book.
- Achieved positive risk management Profit & Loss each year in addition to client trades commissions, and successfully reduced profit volatility through disciplined positioning.
- Worked closely with Quants teams to implement from scratch the new Daiwa Quant Library, by testing pricing models, setting procedures and policies for product pricing and marking market data, and managing Totem submissions (market-wide valuation consensus for OTC derivatives).

JPMorgan Securities Japan Co., Ltd. – Tokyo, Japan April 2006 – June 2009 Associate, Exotics and Hybrids Trading, Equity Derivatives Division

- Risk-managed the Equity Index Exotics and Hybrids book covering auto-callable knock-in structures, and long-dated hybrid products (Enman).
- Managed stock-picking algorithmic strategy book with custom-made JPM i-Max Index. Implemented carry-enhancing with FX forward, Nikkei index-arbitrage.
- Trained with Quantitative Research teams in New York.

EDUCATION

Hitotsubashi University - Tokyo, Japan

April 2000 – March 2006

- Master's degree in Financial Engineering and Mathematical Finance March 2006.
- Bachelor degree, Mathematical Finance, minor in Data Science March 2005. Top 5% of faculty
- One year of intensive Japanese language training at the Osaka University of Foreign Studies

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING

April 2019 – Present

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (Jan 2020 Jan 2023)
- Hands-on experience with AWS services such as Amazon EC2, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, CloudFront, VPC, ELB, AWS Lambda, API Gateway, and CloudFormation.
- Deep Learning Specialization deeplearning.ai
- Fast.ai: Practical Deep Learning for Coders, Deep Learning from Foundations, Code-First Introduction to Natural Language Processing.
- John Hopkins University Data Science Specialization (R, data wrangling, EDA, statistical inference)
- Stanford Machine Learning

LANGUAGE & CODING SKILLS

- Proficient in Python, AWS Automation with Python,
- Working knowledge of data science and deep learning APIs such as PyTorch, fastai, numpy, matplotlib, pandas and scikit-learn as well as R, tidyverse and SQL.
- Advanced fluency in Japanese (Japanese Language Proficiency Test -highest level, 382 / 400 pts)
- Native speaker of French and Wolof, advanced fluency in English (TOEIC 985 pts)

AWARDS & GRANTS

- Japanese government scholarship covering full tuition and living expenses for 6 years
- Winner of Math and English Awards National High-School Academic Olympiads Senegal 1998
- Ranked top high-school student of the country Senegal Baccalaureate 1999.